Hello, peopleish learners. Welcome
back to another great lesson
with English pod. My name is
Marco and I'm Erica and today
We're bringing you another great
lesson about being at the bank.
That's right We've got an
intermediate lesson for you today
With lots of great language to
help you open a bank account.
Okay, so let's look at our
vocabulary preview today
very cavalry preview
Two words today. The first
one is checking accounts.
A checking account.
Checking accounts
So what is a checking
account? Well, it's a type of
bank account that lets you
do your day-to-day or daily
Banking, so it's the normal
bank account that you
used to go shopping that
you used to pay your bills
Yep, exactly the opposite
and our second word is
Savings accounts savings account savings
account. So a savings account is too
It's a bank account where you
save your money to save money.
Right? So usually you
don't touch the money in
this account Yeah,
usually it stays in there
Right, so usually banks will have these two
types of accounts. Yes checking and savings
Okay, great. Let's listen to our
dialogue a first time now All right
Well today we're at a
bank and we're going
to listen as a man is opening a bank account
The dialogue is going to be spoken at a
normal speed so it
might be a little bit fast
Yeah, but don't worry about it because
we'll come back and explain everything
Next piece may help you, sir
Hello, yes, I'd like to open a bank account
Certainly, I can help you
with that. What type of account
would you like to open a
checking or a saving account?
What features do they
offer? Well, if you just
take a look here see
without checking account
You can have unlimited daily
transactions for a small monthly
fee and our savings account
has a higher interest rate
But you must carry a
minimum balance of $10,000 a
See well, I think I'm more
interested in a checking account.
I'd like to have easy
access to my money
All right, then with
this checking account,
you'll be issued a debit
card and a checkbook
We require overdraft protection.
There is an extra fee for that.
No, that won't be necessary
In that case, I'll get you
to fill out this paperwork.
I'll need your social insurance number
and two pieces of government ID
If you could just sign here
and here and here will be all set
Would you like to
make a deposit today?
Yes, I'd like to deposit
one billion dollars
All right, one billion dollars.
That's a lot of money. That's a weird laugh
Okay, let's look at language takeaway today
Language takeaway
Today we've got four words
for you in language takeaway
all about money and banking
money and banking uh-huh
The first one that we have today is
transaction transaction transaction transaction
So we have some great
examples that will help you
understand what a
transaction is so let's listen
Example one
I need a record of my most
recent bank transactions
Example two
There is no fee for bank
transactions done online
Example three
Okay, we have deposited your money. Would
you like to make another transaction today?
So basically I can
understand that a transaction
is moving money around
in your bank accounts
Right. It's taking your money from right
It's taking money from your
bank account and putting it
in another account or just
taking it to spend whatever
Yes, that's a transaction
or even putting money
into your bank accounts.
That's also a transaction
Great our second word
balance balance balance
Your account balance.
Uh-huh is how much money
you have exactly right
at account balance
My account balance is
two dollars right now. I think
That's a bit of a problem. Yes. Good thing
payday is three days away. Yeah. Oh my god
Okay, our third word
overdraft overdraft overdraft
So this really comes in handy, right?
To overdraft.
Can you tell us a little bit about it?
Let's say in my bank account.
I have five hundred dollars
But I spend six hundred
dollars right so I have
an overdraft in my account
meaning I owe the bank
Hundred dollars right. It's
also commonly referred to
as a negative balance.
That's right negative balance
Like me very soon.
I will have a negative balance
Okay, this one is a little
bit tricky to understand
So let's listen to a couple of
examples of how we use this word
Example one
The maximum overdraft on my
account is only five thousand dollars
Example two
I'm sorry sir, but you've
exceeded your maximum
overdraft limit. I cannot
give you any more money
Example three
Oh, no, I have to pay
$1,500 in overdraft fees
Okay great examples now we
can take a look at our last word
debit card debit card debit card
D-E-B-I-T card debit card
So debit card is issued by the bank.
Yes, and used to take money out of a ATM
From an ATM machine
right a debit card not to be
confused with a credit card
not the same thing. Okay
Okay, great So now we could listen to our
dialogue a second time at a slower speed
So now we can you can hear all of
the great language you just talked about
Next, please may I help you sir. Hello.
Yes. I'd like to open a bank account
Certainly I can help you with that
What type of account would you like
to open a checking or a savings account?
What features do they offer?
Well, if you just look here
See with our checking
account you can have
unlimited daily transactions
for a small monthly fee
And our savings account
has a higher interest rate
But you must carry a
minimum balance of $10,000
I see well, I think I'm more
interested in a checking account
I like to have easy access to my money
All right, then with this
checking account you'll
be issued with a debit
card and a checkbook
Will you require
overdraft protection?
There is an extra fee for that.
No, that won't be necessary
In that case, I'll get you
to fill out this paperwork
I'll need your social insurance number
and two pieces of government ID
If you could just sign here
and here and here will be all set
Would you like to make a deposit today?
Yes, I'd like to deposit
one billion dollars
We heard some
interesting phrases of how to
tell somebody to do
something in a polite way
Yes, so let's start with fluency
builder and explain these words
Fluency builder The bank teller
asked this man to do a number
of things in order to open his bank
account And she used some great expressions
Right, let's listen to how she asked the
man to do some things in a polite way. Yes
I'll get you to fill out this paperwork
I'll need your social insurance number
If you could just sign here
So the first thing she said is I'll
get you to fill out this paperwork
I'll get you to right, right?
I'll get you to
So it's just a way of saying
can you please fill this out?
Yeah, do this do this but in a
different way, right? Uh-huh more polite
It's pretty polite
Then she also said I'll need your
social insurance number. I'll need your
I'll need your again a polite way of
saying give me your social insurance number
Give me your social insurance Yeah,
and the last thing she said and this is
really polite if you
could just sign here. Yes
If you could just sign
here if you could just
If you could just wait a
moment, I'll be with you
If you could just send me an
email with your bank account
number right very polite
way of asking for something
Yep, well some great language
in today's cast. Let's listen to the
dialogue one last time and we'll
catch all of this wonderful language
Next please may help you sir
Hello, yes, I'd like to open a bank account
Certainly I can help you with that
what type of account would you like
to open a checking or a saving
account? What features do they offer?
Well, if you just take a look here see
Without checking account
you can have unlimited
daily transactions for
a small monthly fee
And our savings account
has a higher interest rate,
but you must carry a
minimum balance of $10,000
AC well, I think I'm more
interested in a checking account
I'd like to have easy access to my money
All right, then with
this checking account
you'll be issued a debit
card and a checkbook
Will you require overdraft protection?
There was an extra fee for that.
No, that won't be necessary
In that case, I'll get you
to fill out this paperwork.
I'll need your social insurance number
and two pieces of government ID
If you could just sign here
and here and here will be all set
Would you like to make a deposit today?
Yes, I'd like to deposit
one billion dollars
One billion dollars
Okay, so an interesting thing here
Not many countries use checks. That's
right. Right the checkbook or a check
Yeah, it tends to be more of an
American thing. Don't you think?
It is it is I think it is for those of you
who aren't sure what a what a check is
It's basically a piece of paper that
you just sign your name and yeah
You write the amount of money
and then you sign your name, right?
Right, and then you give that
to the person that that person
can take it to the bank and
get money in exchange for yes
It's not very common in other
countries. No, but from what
I know every single American
has a checkbook and uses it
Right the regular yeah, yeah,
for example you pay your phone
bill or your electric bill just
put a check in the mailbox and
It's done
It's an interesting thing also
sometimes in other countries
people salaries are paid through
checks. Yes, pay check. Oh, yes
I see where that word comes from
Paycheck uh-huh, but for example
here in China. It's not very common, right?
I've never seen a check here. Me
neither. What about in your countries?
We'd like to know how
the banking system works
Yes come to our website at
englishpod.com and tell us all about it
Yes, and you can also
leave your questions and
comments on our website
and we'll be there to answer it
Yeah, Marco and I love
answering your questions.
So please visit us right
but until then it's goodbye